Records of the Human Resources Development and Operations Policy Vice Presidency
World Bank Group Archives
- Records of ESP, PSP, and PGP, January 1991 - May 1997; WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_91-04; 27.72 linear feet of textual records; 1 VHS tape; Education and Social Policy Department (ESP), Poverty and Social Policy Department (PSP), and Poverty, Gender, and Public Sector Management Department (PGP)
  - PSP/PGP Director's subject and activity files, January 1992 – May 1997 (predominant July 1995 to December 1996); WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_91-04-04; 16.38 linear feet of textual records; 1 VHS tape
    - Regional Meeting on Cross Support - 1v, 1996-03-19 - 1996-03-27; 01458406
    - Labor Policy Seminar - 1v, 1996-05-15 - ?; 01458405
    - Non-Governmental Organizations [NGO] - Issues - Steering Group Meeting, 1997-05-12; 01458408
    - Urban Poverty Meeting with Mr. Burki - 1v, 1995-12-19 - ?; 01458407
    - Poverty Assessment (OED Report) Briefing with Mr. Wolfensohn - 1v, 1996-11-08 - ?; 01458409
    - Private Sector Management Staffing Group Meeting - 1v, 1996-05-01 - ?; 01458410
    - Poverty Reduction and Economic Management Interim Council Meeting - 1v, 1997-04-15 - ?; 01458411
    - Press Briefing on Poverty Reduction and the World Bank - 1v, 1996-06-20 - ?; 01458412
    - Social Investment Fund's Travel to Guatemala, Honduras and Nicaragua ( LAC Bank-NGO Meeting ) - 1v, 1996-06-07 - 1996-06-16; 01458413
    - Operational Policy Committee Meeting on Poverty ( Progress Report ) - 1v, 1996-04-11 - ?; 01458414
    - Poverty Seminars: Paris, London, Berne - 1v, 1996-09-18 - 1996-09-24; 01458416
    - Denmark, Finland, Sweden: Poverty Seminars - 1v, 1996-12-03 - 1996-12-11; 01458415
    - Sri Lanka: Visit to Poverty Alleviation Projects - 1v, 1997-01-02 - 1997-01-14; 01458417
    - Speeches - 1v, 1993-01-01 - 1996-05-01; 01458334
    - World Summit for Social Development - box, 1993-04-01 - 1996-08-31; 01458927
    - Meeting with NGOs on Poverty at Interaction - 1v, 1995-10-03 - ?; 01458418
    - Performance Indicators to Monitor Poverty Reduction - 1v, 1993-10-01 - 1996-10-01; 01458934
    - Next Step Action Program - 1v, 1994-04-01 - 1995-12-01; 01458932
    - IDA 10 - 1v, 1993-05-01 - 1993-07-31; 01458937
    - PSP Week - 1v, 1996-05-01 - ?; 01458935
    - Program of Targeted Interventions ( PTI ) - 1v, 1993-06-01 - ?; 01458939
    - Social Funds - 1v, 1991-05-01 - 1991-07-31; 01458940
    - IDA 9 - 1v, 1992-06-01 - 1993-08-31; 01458942
    - Informal Working Group on Poverty Reduction - 1v, 1995-04-21 - ?; 01458944
    - Substantial Indicators - 1v, 1993-05-01 - 1993-07-01; 01458943
    - Experts Group Meeting on Poverty ( Lusaka, Zambia ) - 1v, 1994-06-27 - 1994-08-31; 01458949
    - Budget Files - 2v, 1994-02-01 - 1997-01-31; 01458378
    - Networks - 1v, 1996-05-01 - 1997-01-31; 01458335
    - Procedures - HRO - 1v, 1992-11-01 - 1996-08-31; 01458336
    - Procedures - ESP - 1v, 1994-03-01 - 1996-12-31; 01458337
  - PSP briefing letters for World Bank Senior officials, June 1995 – October 1996; WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_91-04-05; 0.41 linear feet of textual records
    This series includes letters prepared by PSP staff for signature or briefing for the Human Capital Development (HCD) Vice President Armeane M. Choski from May 1996 to October 1996, and letters prepared for World Bank President James D. Wolfensohn from June 1995 to September 1996. The letters are related to the functions and activities of the Poverty and Social Policy Department (PSP).
    Arranged chronologically.
    - Letters Prepared for: Acting President, Managing Directors. HCDVP / Acting VP - 1v, 1996-05-01 - 1996-10-31; 01458332
    - Wolfensohn's Letters - 1v, 1995-06-01 - 1996-10-01; 01458333
  - PSP conferences, seminars, symposiums, workshops, and meetings, 1995 - 1997; WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_91-04-06; 3.37 linear feet of textual records
    This series consists of records from conferences, seminars, symposiums, workshops, and meetings organized or participated in by the Poverty and Social Policy Department (PSP). Some seminars, workshops, and meetings are organized by the specific teams or groups of PSP. Other events are organized in collaboration with NGOs, outside agencies, or other World Bank units. The records include: memoranda; correspondence; agenda and minutes; itineraries; printouts of presentation slides; speech transcripts; articles; programs; brochures; PSP produced reports; external reports; and post event follow-up reports. The events organized solely by PSP or one of its teams or groups contain planning records, such as proposed events, speakers, content, and budget information.
    The conferences, seminars, symposiums, workshops, and meetings records have no apparent system of arrangement.
    - Conference on Evaluation and Development - Operations Evaluation Department [OED] - April 1 and 2, 1997 - Correspondence, 1997-03-17 - 1997-04-02; 01458380
    - International Meeting on the 20/20 Initiative in Oslo, Norway - 1v, 1996-04-23 - 1996-04-25; 01458381
    - Seminar on Globalization and Liberalization: Effects of International Economic Relations on Poverty in UNCTAD, Palais Des Nations, Geneva - 1v, 1996-03-01 - 1996-05-01; 01458382
    - The World Bank Second Conference on Evaluation and Development - The Institutional Dimension, 1997-01-31 - 1997-04-02; 01458379
    - Fourth World Conference on Women in Beijing, China - 1v, 1995-08-01 - 1995-10-01; 01458383
    - Regional Seminar on the Future Role of Social Investment funds in Montelimar, Nicaragua - 1v, 1995-12-01 - 1996-05-31; 01458384
    - International Workshop on Social Funds - 1v, 1997-05-01 - ?; 01458386
    - EDI - PSP Meeting on Social Investment Funds - 1v, 1996-10-28 - ?; 01458389
    - Inter-Agency Learning Group on Participation - 1v, 1995-09-18 - 1995-09-19; 01458392
    - Collaboration with LLC on Training - 1v, 1996-04-24 - ?; 01458952
    - Inter-Agency Group on Participation and Resource Persons - 1v, 1996-03-28 - 1996-03-29; 01458393
    - The External Gender Consultative Group Meeting - 1v, 1996-04-29 - 1996-04-30; 01458394
    - NGO Seminar on Private Sector Development - 1v, 1996-06-06 - ?; 01458395
    - FIAHS '97: Allocation and Management of Funds - 1v, 1996-09-10 - ?; 01458397
    - Seminar on Public Management Lessons for Developing Countries and the World Bank - 1v, 1996-06-01 - ?; 01458398
    - Post Conflict Informal Meeting - 1v, 1996-10-01 - ?; 01458399
    - The World Bank and The United Nations High Commission on Human Rights - 1v, 1996-07-24 - 1996-07-25; 01458396
    - Symposium on Public Sector Management - 1v, 1996-12-01 - ?; 01458400
    - Workshop on the Future of Poverty Analysis - 1v, 1997-03-18 - ?; 01458401
    - Symposium on Sustainable Development: Implications for World Peace - 1v, 1996-03-27 - 1996-03-29; 01458402
    - Conference on Troubled States - 1v, 1996-06-21 - ?; 01458403
    - Institute for Policy Studies - 1v, 1997-02-03 - ?; 01458404
  - ESP, PSP, and PGP chronological files, February 1994 – May 1997; WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_91-04-01; 5.04 linear feet of textual records
    The series contains chronological files created by: the Education and Social Policy Department (ESP); the Poverty and Social Policy Department (PSP); and the Poverty, Gender, and Public Sector Management Department (PGP). Two separate sets of departmental chronological files are contained in this series: one for ESP; and another for PSP and PGP. The ESP chronological files consist of records related to: policy development; departmental contributions to external projects, reviews, and policy development; conference and seminar attendance and participation; and assistance to and collaboration with the Regions. Records include: memoranda; meeting briefing notes, agendas, and minutes; comments on research and policy papers and Country Assistance Strategy (CAS) papers; Terms of Reference; back-to-office reports; and progress reports. The ESP departmental chronological files are mostly correspondence with attachments and memoranda between ESP Director Kingsley Y. Amoako, ESP staff, and other World Bank units. Records within ESP departmental chronological files from July 1995 to December 1995 contain records created and received by both ESP and PSP, due to the transition period of ESP staff into PSP.
    The separate PSP/PGP departmental chronological files consist of similar records between PSP/PGP Director Ishrat Husain, PSP staff, PGP staff, and other World Bank units. Additional PSP chronological files were also maintained for incoming and outgoing correspondence between Husain and external agencies and individuals from May 1995 to May 1997. Incoming and outgoing faxes and emails files between Husain, PSP staff, and other World Bank units are maintained from July 1995 to May 1997. PSP correspondence and memoranda from mid-1996 discuss the mapping of PSP Groups into the HD, ESSD, and PREM Networks. PGP related records are contained in chronological files dated January 1997 to May 1997 when PGP was temporarily created to transition into the PREM Network.
    ESP chronological files are arranged chronologically. PSP/PGP chronological files are subdivided into the following folders: faxes; relevant email; letters; and memos. The subdivided folders are thereunder arranged chronologically.
    - Departmental Chrons - box, 1995-12-01 - 1997-05-31; 01458330
    - Departmental Chrons - box, 1994-03-01 - 1997-05-31; 01458331
    - Education and Social Policy [ESP] Department - General File - 1994 Chronological File - Volume 1, 1994-02-16 - 1994-03-30; 01337950
    - Education and Social Policy [ESP] Department - General File - 1994 Chronological File - Volume 2, 1994-04-01 - 1994-04-28; 01337951
    - Education and Social Policy [ESP] Department - General File - 1994 Chronological File - Volume 3, 1994-05-02 - 1994-05-31; 01337952
    - Education and Social Policy [ESP] Department - General File - 1994 Chronological File - Volume 5, 1994-07-01 - 1994-07-28; 01337954
    - Education and Social Policy [ESP] Department - General File - 1994 Chronological File - Volume 4, 1994-05-03 - 1994-06-29; 01337953
    - Education and Social Policy [ESP] Department - General File - 1994 Chronological File - Volume 6, 1994-08-01 - 1994-08-29; 01337955
    - Education and Social Policy [ESP] Department - General File - 1994 Chronological File - Volume 7, 1994-09-01 - 1994-09-30; 01337956
    - Education and Social Policy [ESP] Department - General File - 1994 Chronological File - Volume 8, 1994-09-28 - 1994-10-31; 01337957
    - Education and Social Policy [ESP] Department - General File - 1994 Chronological File - Volume 9, 1994-11-01 - 1994-11-30; 01337958
    - Education and Social Policy [ESP] Department - General File - 1994 Chronological File - Volume 10, 1994-12-01 - 1994-12-30; 01337959
    - Education and Social Policy [ESP] Department - General File - 1995 Chronological File - Volume 1, 1995-01-03 - 1995-02-28; 01337960
    - Education and Social Policy [ESP] Department - General File - 1995 Chronological File - Volume 3, 1995-07-03 - 1995-07-17; 01337962
    - Education and Social Policy [ESP] Department - General File - 1995 Chronological File - Volume 2, 1995-03-01 - 1995-04-28; 01337961
    - Education and Social Policy [ESP] Department - General File - 1995 Chronological File - Volume 4, 1995-04-05 - 1995-06-28; 01337963
    - Education and Social Policy [ESP] Department - General File - 1995 Chronological File - Volume 5, 1995-07-19 - 1995-09-28; 01337964
    - Education and Social Policy [ESP] Department - General File - 1995 Chronological File - Volume 6, 1995-08-23 - 1995-10-31; 01337965
    - Education and Social Policy [ESP] Department - General File - 1995 Chronological File - Volume 7, 1995-11-01 - 1995-12-21; 01337966
  - ESP and PSP Discussion Paper Series records, September 1993 – January 1997; WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_91-04-03; 1.26 linear feet of textual records
    This series consists of discussion papers produced by staff in the Education and Social Policy Department (ESP) and the Poverty and Social Policy Department (PSP) for the departments Discussion Paper Series. The Discussion Paper Series includes papers on numerous topics related to the functions of ESP and PSP. The papers produced for this Series were not meant to be published as final products or reports, but were intended to stimulate discussion and comment internally among ESP and PSP staff, and provide up to date analysis to operational staff. The discussion papers also served as preliminary analysis for subsequent policy and best practice papers meant for publication and dissemination to an external audience.
    The Discussion Paper Series records have no apparent system of arrangement.
    - selected social safety net programs in the Philippes: targeting, cost-effectiveness and options for reform - E, 1995-11-01 - ?; 01458537
    - Armenia: A poverty profile - E, 1995-11-01 - ?; 01458535
    - An Assessment of Trends in Poverty in Ghana 1988 - 1992 - Harold Coulombe, Andrew McKay - Poverty and Social Policy Department [PSP] Discussion Paper Series - Paper 81 - November 1995, 1995-11-01; 01458532
    - Opportunistic Government or sustaining reform ? electoral trends and public expenditure patterns in Peru, 1990 - 1995 - E, 1996-03-01 - ?; 01458518
    - Regulatory costs and employment in the informal sector of Argentina - E, 1994-10-01 - ?; 01458507
    - Strategies for enhancing the political sustainability of reform in Ukraine - E, 1995-01-01 - ?; 01458506
    - Social funds: strengths, weaknesses, and conditions for success - E, 1995-01-01 - ?; 01458504
    - Poverty, deregulation and employment in the informal sector of Mexico - E, 1995-03-01 - ?; 01458500
    - The old and new poor in Russia: trends in poverty - E, 1995-04-01 - ?; 01458495
    - On the Design of Social Safety Nets - E, 1995-05-01 - ?; 01458491
    - Social assistance and the poor in Romania - E, 1995-05-01 - ?; 01458489
    - systematic interventions in urban poverty - E, 1994-07-01 - ?; 01458472
    - Market failure and policy failure in alleviating urban poverty - E, 1994-07-01 - ?; 01458469
    - Sociocultural factors affecting Science learning and attitude - E, 01458704
    - Promotion of self-employment: Experience in OECD and transitional economies - E, 1994-06-01 - ?; 01458702
    - The impact of public health spending on poverty and inequality in South Africa - E, 1996-12-01 - ?; 01458542
    - Poverty and inequality in the distribution of public education spending in South Africa - E, 1996-12-01 - ?; 01458541
    - Who uses basic services in rural El Salvador ? - E, 1997-01-01 - ?; 01458539
    - The incidence of social spending in Ghana - E, 1995-11-01 - ?; 01458528
    - Poverty assessment in Ghana using qualitative and participatory research methods - E, 1995-11-01 - ?; 01458525
    - Accounting for the Reduction in Rural Poverty in Ghana 1988 - 1992 - Christine Jones, Xiao Ye - Poverty and Social Policy Department [PSP] Discussion Paper Series - Paper 84 - November 1995, 1995-11-01; 01458521
    - sector work and project performance in education: a review of bank experience - E, 1996-01-01 - ?; 01458520
    - Protecting the disadvantaged in a high growth economy: safety nets in Thailand - E, 1996-07-01 - ?; 01458512
    - Labor market flexibility and job security measures in a global economy: new challenges ahead - E, 1994-10-01 - ?; 01458508
    - From Second Economy to Informal Sector: The Russian Labor Market in Transition - E, 1995-04-01 - ?; 01458493
    - Performance indicators to monitor poverty reduction - E, 1995-06-01 - ?; 01458487
    - Poverty, inequality and growth - E, 1995-06-01 - ?; 01458486
    - Regulatory costs and poverty reduction in the mocrofirm sector: a synthesis of Latin American case studies - E, 1995-06-01 - ?; 01458485
    - A review of the World Bank's efforts to assist African governments in reducing poverty - E, 1993-09-01 - ?; 01458483
    - Country policies for poverty reduction a review of poverty assessments - E, 1993-10-01 - ?; 01458482
    - Implementing projects for the poor: what have we achieved ? - E, 1995-06-01 - ?; 01458484
    - How to raise the effectiveness of secondary schools ? universal and locally tailored investment strategies - E, 1994-06-01 - ?; 01458480
    - Rethinking the World Bank's social insurance analysis - E, 1994-06-01 - ?; 01458476
    - ESP discussion paper; series abstracts nos. 42-70 - E, 1995-06-01 - ?; 01458312
  - ESP and PSP Annual Progress Report on Poverty (APPR), 1991 - 1996; WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_91-04-02; 1.26 linear feet of textual records
    This series includes records related to the Annual Poverty Progress Report (APPR) prepared by the Education and Social Policy Department (ESP) and the Poverty and Social Policy Department (PSP). At the request of the Bank's Executive Board of Directors and the Office of the President (EXC), the ESP was given the responsibility of producing an annual report that gauged the progression of the Poverty Reduction Strategy outlined in the Bank's World Development Report (WDR) 1990: Poverty. The APPRs were scheduled to be published for the fiscal years 1993 to 1995. The reports were prepared by the Monitoring Unit of the Poverty Analysis and Policy team in ESP and later PSP. The bulk of poverty progress information was collected from the poverty assessment reports and assessment summaries produced by operational staff in the Regional Vice Presidencies. The APPRs were presented to the Executive Board, the Operational Policy Committee (OPC), and EXC for comment, review, and approval. The APPRs were then used as the official publication for dissemination to audiences external to the Bank, and were subsequently presented at Poverty Dissemination Seminars organized by the World Bank in partnership with various international development agencies, NGOs, government agencies, and academic institutions.
    The records in this series includes background history and reference material on the Poverty Reduction Strategy and the 1990 WDR, including: a copy of the policy paper "Assistance Strategies to Reduce Poverty" (1991); and memoranda, agenda, meeting minutes, and a communiqu? related to the joint IMF and World Bank Development Committee from April 1992 regarding reporting on the Poverty Reduction Strategy. The records additionally consist of APPR drafts for 1992 to 1995, and a published APPR copy of the Poverty Reduction and the World Bank: Progress and Challenges in the 1990s for fiscal year 1995. Memoranda, correspondence, and back-to-office reports detail meetings with the Executive Board, OPC, and EXC related to the APPRs, and follow-up actions taken by ESP and PSP. Numerous World Bank press releases and external articles related to the APPRs are also included.
    The series also includes records related to the Poverty Dissemination Seminars attended by World Bank staff in Europe from 1993 to 1994. These records consist of: memoranda; agenda and meeting minutes; correspondence; invitation letters to participants; speech transcripts of World Bank staff; external reports on poverty issues; and copies of the World Bank published APPRs. The memoranda and correspondence consist of planning arrangements between ESP/ PSP and other World Bank units for seminars. Other memoranda and correspondence are post--seminar reports or summaries of responses to the APPR from external organizations and individuals.
    Arranged by subject and thereunder chronologically by year.
    - Policy Paper: Assistance Strategies to Reduce Poverty - 1v, 1991-07-01 - ?; 01458946
    - Annual Poverty Progress Report - 2v, 1992-04-01 - 1996-12-31; 01458897
    - Annual Report on Poverty - Poverty Seminars, Europe - 2v, 1992-12-01 - 1993-10-31; 01458898